Guide to the Elizabeth Hudson Collection of E. Œ. Somerville and Personal Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Elizabeth Hudson collection of E. Œ. Somerville and personal papers
1879-1970
GEN MSS 28
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
10
20 boxes + 2 broadside, 1 art
Collection contains correspondence, writings, drawings and paintings, and other papers documenting the life of E. Œ. Somerville, as well as materials related to Elizabeth Hudson's interest in the military and her involvement in the relief efforts of World Wars I and II. Correspondence includes letters to Hudson from the Chiswick Press, Hildegarde Coghill, Geraldine Cummins, Edith Somerville, Moira Somerville, and A. J. A. Symons concerning the Somerville family's life in Ireland, Edith Somerville's writing, and efforts by Hudson and Somerville to publish a bibliography of the works of Somerville and Ross. Other letters include correspondence between Somerville and various individuals and some third-party letters. Writings include drafts and proofs of Hudson's Somerville and Ross bibliography, typescript copies of portions of Somerville's diary, and a typescript of Somerville's play Flurry's Wedding. Artwork contains original and reproduction drawings and paintings by Somerville. Photographs include pictures of Somerville, her sister Hildegarde Coghill and others. Other materials include notes and papers related to the bibliography and to Somerville's writing in general, as well as transcriptions of automatic writing and spiritual communications with Somerville, her cousin Martin Ross, and Hudson's friend and companion Dorothy Sturges. Papers related to war and the military document Hudson's service in the American Red Cross Military Hospital No. 1 during World War I, and her involvement in relief efforts for France during World War II. Included are letters to Hudson from soldiers, nurses and children, photographs of Paris, military hospitals, soldiers and nurses, scrapbooks of newspaper clippings, and other papers.
Hudson, Elizabeth
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Elizabeth Hudson, 1968.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Restricted Fragile material in boxes 20-21 may be consulted only with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies or photographic prints for reference use have been substituted in the main files.
Associated Materials
Elizabeth Hudson Papers (MS 1464). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Elizabeth Hudson Papers (LWL MSS 20). Lewis Walpole Library, Yale University.
E. OE. SOMERVILLE (1858-1949)
Edith Anna Oenone Somerville was born on 2 May 1858 in Corfu, Greece, where her father, a British army lieutenant colonel, was stationed. He retired to Ireland a year later, and Somerville grew up at Drishane House in County Cork. She attended Alexandra College and studied painting in London, Dusseldorf and Paris, but soon returned to Ireland.
In January of 1886, Somerville first met her younger cousin Violet Martin (almost always referred to as Martin Ross). The two began writing together, and in 1889 they published their first book, An Irish Cousin. They went on to collaborate on fourteen books, their most famous being the novel, The Real Charlotte (1894) and a collection of stories, Some Experiences of an Irish R.M. (1899). They lived together for many years at Drishane House, also traveling around Ireland and Europe. They were both accomplished horsewomen and enthusiastic fox hunters. In 1889 Martin suffered a riding accident from which she never fully recovered. She died in 1915, and while Somerville continued to write, her works did not receive the acclaim she enjoyed with her cousin.
After Martin's death, Somerville often traveled abroad. She also became interested in spiritualism and spirit writings, befriending the medium Geraldine Cummins, and frequently attempting to contact her cousin and other relatives who had passed away. Somerville died in Ireland on 3 October 1949.
ELIZABETH HUDSON (1885-1973)
Mary Elizabeth Hudson was born in Newport, Rhode Island, on April 25, 1885, the daughter of Rev. Robert Hudson and Mary Mosgrove Hudson. Raised in Syracuse, New York, where her father was rector of Trinity Church. Elizabeth Hudson attended Miss Porter's School in Farmington, Connecticut, and returned to Syracuse to work with Memorial Hospital's social services. She traveled to France during World War I to assist in the relief efforts for children left destitute by the war. While in France, she trained as a volunteer nurse, and served at the American Military Hospital No. 1 (also known as the American Ambulance Hospital) in Paris. She also served as a "marraine de guerre," a correspondent with soldiers, many of whom wrote to her even after the war. During World War II, Hudson served on the board of directors for the Coordinating Council of French Relief Societies.
Around 1925, she wrote to the Irish author Edith Somerville, and soon after, paid a visit to Somerville in Ireland. The two became friends, writing and visiting each other frequently. After the death of Hudson's good friend and companion, Dorothy Sturges (1889-1933), Somerville comforted Hudson by trying to contact Sturges using automatic writing. In the early 1930s Hudson began compiling a bibliography of first editions of books by Somerville and Ross. The project was postponed, first by the slowness of the editor who accepted the project, A. J. A. Symons, then by the outbreak of World War II, and finally by the death of Symons. A Bibliography of the First Editions of the Works of OE. Somerville and Martin Ross was eventually published in 1942 by the Sporting Gallery and Bookshop in New York. Elizabeth Hudson died in New York City on May 2, 1973.
Scope and Contents
The Elizabeth Hudson Collection of E. OE. Somerville consists of material related to Somerville collected by Hudson, as well as material related to Hudson's involvement in relief work during World War I and World War II. The collection contains correspondence, writings, artwork, photographs, notes, lists, financial papers, and other material. The papers have been arranged into six series: Correspondence, Writings, Artwork, Photographs, Other Materials Related to Somerville, and Papers Related to War and the Military. The papers span the years 1879-1970, with the bulk between 1916-1950.
Series I, Correspondence (1920-1970), contains letters to Hudson, letters to and from Somerville, and third-party correspondence. The letters to Elizabeth Hudson include many letters from Somerville, describing her life from the 1920s until her death in 1949. The letters discuss the efforts to publish Hudson's Somerville and Ross bibliography, the writing and publication of several of Somerville's own books, exhibitions and sales of her drawings, paintings and manuscripts, her travels to the United States and Hudson's visits to Ireland, and the impact of World War II on her life in Ireland. The letters also discuss in depth Somerville's interest in spiritualism and spirit writing, and many of the letters contain transcripts of Somerville's communications with her cousin Martin Ross and with Hudson's friend Dorothy Sturges. Also included are letters to Hudson from other members of the Somerville family, Geraldine Cummins, A. J. A. Symons of the First Editions Club, who originally planned to publish Hudson's Somerville bibliography, and from the Chiswick Press and the Sporting Gallery and Bookshop, who were also involved in the publication of the book. Other correspondence includes letters between Somerville and Maurice Baring, the Chiswick Press, Harry Worcester Smith, Dorothy Sturges, and A. J. A. Symons. Third-Party Correspondence includes letters from the Chiswick Press, A. Edward Newton and A. J. A. Symons.
Series II, Writings (1926-1939), contains drafts and proofs of Hudson's A Bibliography of the First Editions of the Works of E. OE. Somerville & Martin Ross, typescript drafts and galley proofs of Harry Worcester Smith's foreword to The Hitchcock Edition of Somerville and Ross, typescript copies of portions of Somerville's diary pertaining to Hudson, and a typescript of Somerville's play, Flurry's Wedding.
Series III, Artwork (1879-1933), contains original artwork and reproductions of drawings by Somerville, several of her watercolor paintings, a scrapbook with drawings and watercolors, and a sketchbook of early drawings from 1883. Also included is a pencil sketch by an unidentified artist and a reproduction of a drawing of Bradford Johnson, signed by Geoffrey Dodge.
Series IV, Photographs (1903-1948), consists of photographs of Somerville alone and with various friends and relatives, including her sister Hildegarde Coghill and her friend Sylvia Warren, an album containing several photographs of Somerville, as well as a photograph of Drishane House, and one of Martin Ross's family residence, Ross House.
Series V, Other Materials Related to Somerville (1927-1968), includes notes and financial papers related to Hudson's bibliography of Somerville and Ross, and notes, lists and other papers related to writings and artwork by Somerville. Also included in this series are holograph and typescript transcripts of Somerville's spiritualist communications with Dorothy Sturges, as well as Geraldine Cummins's communications with Somerville after Somerville's death. Other materials include newspaper clippings, descriptions of horses by Sylvia Warren, and a ring worn by Somerville.
Series VI, Papers Related to War and the Military (1898-1951), contains letters, photographs, clippings and other papers related to Hudson's experiences during World War I and World War II, and two early scrapbooks compiled by Hudson containing newspaper clippings and other items related to the military. The correspondence consists of letters from World War I soldiers to Hudson, many of whom she treated as a nurse, giving her news about their lives at the front and in military hospitals. Other letters to Hudson include letters from other women involved in the relief efforts, letters from Augustine Ingold, a disabled child who was living in various sanatoriums during World War I, and other letters related to Hudson's involvement in the relief efforts during both world wars. Letters from Hudson include both original and draft letters to several of the soldiers who wrote to her.
Photographs in this series include individual pictures of soldiers, children, and others. Also included are two photograph albums from World War I. One, containing photographs taken in France of soldiers, nurses, many children under the protection of the Comité franco-américain pour la protection des enfants de la frontière, buildings, and landscapes, was presumably assembled by Hudson. The second scrapbook was compiled by Hudson's friend Dorothy Sturges and contains two of Sturges's passports, a report on Le bien-être du blessé (Woman's Motor Unit), several letters to Sturges, and photographs of members of the motor unit, soldiers, military hospital wards, Paris landmarks and the destruction caused by the bombing. Other papers include invitations and programs for relief effort benefit events, typescripts of speeches about World War II, Hudson's travel permits from World War I, and printed memorabilia from World War II.
Authors, Irish -- 20th Century; Military nursing -- France; Spirit writings; Spiritualism; Women authors; World War, 1914-1918 -- Hospitals, charities, etc.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Medical care; World War, 1914-1918 -- Women; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1939-1945; Drawings (visual works); Photograph albums; Photographic prints; Scrapbooks; Spirit Communications; Watercolors (paintings); Authors; Nurses; Coghill, Hildegarde; Cummins, Geraldine, 1890-1969; Hudson, Elizabeth; Ross, Martin, 1862-1915; Somerville, E. Œ. (Edith Œnone), 1858-1949; Somerville, Moira; Symons, A. J. A. (Alphonse James Albert), 1900-1941; United States. Army. American Expeditionary Force. American Red Cross Military Hospital No. 1 (Paris, France); Chiswick Press
- Correspondence, 1920-1970; Series I; 1.45; (4 boxes)
  - LETTERS TO ELIZABETH HUDSON
    - From E. OE. Somerville
      - Letters, 1925-32 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
      - Letters, 1933-35 (Box 1, Folder 7-15)
      - Letters, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 16-23)
        Scope and Contents
        Includes: Letters to ES from The First Edition Club, 1936 Sep 14; Ruth Stillman, [1936] Nov 10
      - Letters, 1937-39 (Box 2, Folder 24-34)
        Includes: Letters to ES from Cyril Clemens, 1937 Jun 15; A. J. A. Symons, 1937 Jul 19 and 1937 Oct 7
      - Letters, 1940-44 (Box 2, Folder 35-46)
        Includes: Letters to ES from Chiswick Press, 1941 Sep 17, 1942 Aug 25; The First Edition Club, 1943 Jul 13; Heinemann (Firm), 1944 Jul 7
      - Letters, 1945-49, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 47-54)
    - From others
      - Adams, ----, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Anstey[?], C. A., 1937 Feb 21 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Bulcraig & Davis (Firm), 1943 Jul 1 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Cable and Radio Censor. Office of Censorship, 1942 Sep 12 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Chiswick Press, 1941-48, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 59-61)
        Includes: Copies of letters from EH, 5 December 1941, 10 April 1943
      - Clampitt, Helen, 1938 Sep 23 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - Coghill, Hildegarde (ES's sister), 1935-50, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 63-64)
      - Coghill, Patrick (ES's nephew), 1949-68, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - Colony Club (New York, N.Y.), 1943 Nov 4 (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - Cosmopolitan Club (New York, N.Y.), 1943 Nov 5 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - Coward-McCann Inc., 1942, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - Cummins, Geraldine, 1949-52, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - Devin-Adair Company, 1948-49 (Box 4, Folder 70)
      - Edgar H. Wells & Co., [n.y.] Jul 8 (Box 4, Folder 71)
      - Farrar & Rinehart, 1936 Oct 6 (Box 4, Folder 72)
      - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 73)
      - King, Raphael, 1946 Jul 17 (Box 4, Folder 74)
      - Lark, Charles Tressler, 1936 Jan 9 (Box 4, Folder 75)
      - "Mother", 1940 Oct 28 (Box 4, Folder 76)
      - Powell, Lady Violet Georgiana, 1969-70 (Box 4, Folder 77)
      - Sieveking, Lance, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 78)
      - Smith, Sydney R., 1945 Dec 24 (Box 4, Folder 79)
      - Somerville, Cameron (ES's brother), 1935-40, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 80)
      - Somerville, Desmond (ES's nephew), 1937-51 (Box 4, Folder 81)
      - Somerville, Jack[?] (ES's brother), 1936-49 (Box 4, Folder 82)
      - Somerville, Moira (Desmond's wife), 1946-51, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 83-84)
      - Sporting Gallery and Bookshop, Inc., 1941-49, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 85)
        Includes: Copy of a reply from EH
      - Sullivan, Mary, 1938, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 86)
        Includes: Copy of a letter from Sullivan to ES
      - Symons, A. J. A. (Alphonse James Albert), 1932-41, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 87-90)
      - Symons, Julian, 1941 Aug 16 (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - United States. Embassy (Great Britain), 1941-42 (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - Wallach, Jane, [n.y.] Mar 15 (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - Warren, Sylvia, 1936-39, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - Whitney, John Hay (copy), 1935 Nov 27 (Box 4, Folder 95)
      - Unidentified, 1936-1949 (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - LETTERS FROM E. OE. SOMERVILLE
    - Hitchcock, Mrs. Thomas, 1927 Oct 7 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Penrose, Evelyn, 1928 May 17 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Robinson, Lennox, 1936 Apr 25 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Smith, Harry Worcester, 1924-29 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Stone, Melville E., 1936 Oct 29 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Sturges, Dorothy, 1929 May 4 (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - LETTERS TO E. OE. SOMERVILLE
    - Baring, Maurice, 1920, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Bickers and Son, Ltd., 1939 Jul 21 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - British Museum, 1943 Jul 16 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Chiswick Press, 1942 Apr 27 (Box 4, Folder 106)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Box 2, folders 37 and 42
    - Clemens, Cyril
      See: Box 2, folder 25
    - Constable (Firm), 1933 Dec 14 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Coward-McCann Inc., 1936 Nov 23 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Ely, Carl B., 1935, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Farrar, John (copy), 1936 Oct 6 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - The First Edition Club
      See: Box 1, folder 19
      See: Box 2, folder 44
    - Greenslet, Ferris
      See: Box 4, folder 112
    - Heinemann (Firm), 1933 Nov 10 (Box 4, Folder 111)
      See also: Box 2, folder 46
    - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1942 Oct 22 (Box 4, Folder 112)
      Includes: Letter from Ferris Greenslet
    - Ivor, Nicholson & Watson Ltd., 1933 Nov 13 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Longman Green & Co. (copy), 1927 May 26 (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Methuen & Co., 1933 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Smith, Harry Worcester (copies), 1924-27 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Stillman, Ruth
      See: Box 1, folder 22
    - Stone, Melville E., 1936 Oct 10 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Sullivan, Mary
      See: Box 4, folder 86
    - Suzannet, Alain de, comte, 1943 Feb 17 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Symons, A. J. A. (Alphonse James Albert), 1932-36, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 119)
      See also: Box 2, folders 25-26
    - William Blackwood and Sons Ltd., 1933 Dec 5 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Unidentified envelope, 1930 (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - THIRD-PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Boston Athenæum Library to "Mrs. Beebe", 1943 Feb 6 (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Chiswick Press to A. J. A. (Alphonse James Albert) Symons, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Devin-Adair Company to Geraldine Cummins, 1951 May 15 (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Newton, A. Edward (Alfred Edward) to Harry Worcester Smith, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - [Smith, Harry Worcester?] to Longman Green & Co. (copy), 1927 Oct 31 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Symons, A. J. A. (Alphonse James Albert) to undentified (form letter), 1939, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 127)
- Writings, 1926-1939; Series II; 0.4; (1 box)
  - HUDSON, ELIZABETH
    - Bibliography
      [Full title: A Bibliography of the First Editions of the Works of E. Oe. Somerville & Martin Ross ]
      - Holograph draft, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 128-129)
      - Typescript, corrected, of the foreword by EH, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 130)
      - Partial carbon typescript and holograph draft (Box 5, Folder 131-133)
      - Carbon typescript draft, corrected, with holograph notes in EH's[?] hand (Box 5, Folder 134-136)
      - Typescript and holograph draft, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 137-138)
      - Typescript and holograph draft, with notes by ES, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 139-141)
      - Proofs, with holograph corrections by ES and EH[?], 2 copies, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 142-143)
      - Proofs, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - SMITH, HARRY WORCESTER
    - Foreword to The Hitchcock Edition of Somerville and Ross
      - Typescript, with holograph corrections by George H. Sargent, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 145)
      - Carbon typescript, corrected (4 copies, not identical), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 146-147)
      - Galley proofs, n.d.
  - SOMERVILLE, E. OE.
    - "Excerpts from the Diary of Edith Somerville," typescript, 1933-39 (Box 5, Folder 148)
      Contains entries relating to EH
    - Flurry's Wedding, typescript play, corrected, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 149)
      Includes: Holograph sheet music for a song titled "Indy's Black Eyes"
- Artwork, 1879-1933; Series III; 0.2; (1 box)
  - EDITH SOMERVILLE
    - "Chez Pasteur," reproduction of a drawing, n.d.
    - Child, reproduction of a drawing, n.d.
    - "Come Back to Erin!" pencil and watercolor[?] drawing of 2 dogs and a car (Box 6, Folder 150)
    - "Happy Days!" drawing of a woman dancing, reproduction (Box 6, Folder 151)
    - Hunt scene, pencil, with an ink drawing of a child on horseback on verso, n.d.
    - Hunt scene, reproduction, n.d.
    - Man, reproduction of a drawing, n.d.
    - Man and tailor[?], reproduction of a drawing
    - Man in robe, reproduction of a drawing, n.d.
    - Man with hat and umbrella, reproduction of a drawing
    - "Rachel," pencil drawing of a dog, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 152)
    - Scrapbook with drawings and watercolors
    - "The Silver Fox," ink drawing, from The Silver Fox, chapter 1, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 153)
    - Sketchbook containing pencil drawings, 1883 (Box 6, Folder 154)
    - "Strayaways: At the River's Edge," gouache[?], used as frontispiece in The Silver Fox, n.d.
    - "They Dropped Down out of Sight," watercolor, from The Silver Fox, chapter 12, n.d.
    - "They're Away Up the Mountain Entirely!" pencil drawing of a hunt, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - "A Venerable Farmer-Neighbor," ink portrait of a man, reproduced in chapter 4 of The Smile and the Tear, [1933?] (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - "Walking Out," ink drawing of men and hounds (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - 4 watercolor landscapes, 1879, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Woman[?], reproduction of a drawing, n.d.
    - Woman with child, reproduction of a drawing, n.d.
  - OTHER ARTWORK
    - Boy with dog, sketches of hand on verso, pencil (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Reproduction of a drawing of Bradford Johnson, signed by Geoffrey Dodge, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 160)
- Photographs, 1903-1948; Series IV; 0.2; (.5 box)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF E. OE. SOMERVILLE
    - Album (Box 7, Folder 161)
      Includes: Photographs of ES in her studio, with horses and dogs, and in Providence (R.I.). Also includes 2 photographs of Drishane House and its surroundings
    - In academic robes, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 162)
    - In library with dog (2 copies), n.d.
    - "Miss E. OE. Somerville, the Master of the West Carbery Hounds, watching the pack at work in typical 'Carbery Country'," clipping of printed version (Box 7, Folder 163)
    - Signing a book, [1947-48?]
    - "The West Carberry Hounds: Tim Crowley on Rayleen, E. OE. Somerville on Bridget, Johnny McCarthy on Moses," signed by Elliot T. Fay, 1903
    - With 2 dogs, signed with Christmas greeting by ES, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - With Hildegarde Coghill and Sylvia Warren, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - With an unidentified woman [Edith Hudson], Providence, Rhode Island (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - OTHER PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Drishane House, 1931 (Box 7, Folder 167)
    - Ross House, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 168)
- Other Materials Related to Somerville, 1927-1968; Series V; 0.2; (.5 box)
  - PAPERS RELATING TO ELIZABETH HUDSON'S BIBLIOGRAPHY
    - Bill to ES from "Mrs. Marks" for typing the bibliography, 1933 Nov 33 (Box 7, Folder 169)
    - Chiswick Press. Financial statements addressed to EH, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - Money order to Chiswick Press from EH, 1942 Aug 18 (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - Sales catalogs, 1936-42 (Box 7, Folder 172)
    - Sporting Gallery and Bookshop, Inc. Consignment receipts for the bibliography, 1943-51 (Box 7, Folder 173)
    - Typescript extract of a letter by ES from 17 August 1942 to an unidentified recipient regarding the bibliography, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - PAPERS RELATING TO WORKS BY E. OE. SOMERVILLE
    - Holograph notes on writings by Somerville and Ross (Box 7, Folder 175)
    - Lists of writings and artworks by ES, 1928-39, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Order form for books by Somerville and Ross for members of the Irish Book Club, [ca. 1949?] (Box 7, Folder 177)
      Includes: Barrington, Margaret. "Portrait of an Irish Lady," printed article
    - Order form for An Incorruptible Irishman, with corrections, [1932?] (Box 7, Folder 178)
      Includes: Original ink drawing
    - Order form for The States Through Irish Eyes, [1930?] (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Sales catalog from the Derrydale Press including works by ES, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Sample title pages for The Hitchcock Edition of Somerville and Ross, [1927?] (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - EXHIBITION CATALOGS
    - "Drawings and Paintings: E. OE. Somerville," catalog from an exhibition at the gallery of Mrs. Cornelius J. Sullivan, [n.y.] Jan (Box 7, Folder 182)